<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
  xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
  xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
  >
  <channel>
    <title>npm awesome</title>
    <atom:link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/npmawesome" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://npmawesome.com</link>
    <description>Daily dose of awesome NPM modules for Node.js, old and new!</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 16:39:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>daily</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>2</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>awesomeness</generator>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 16:39:26 GMT</pubDate>

    
    
    
      
      
      
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[agenda]]></title>
        <link><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-05-05-agenda]]></link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Gorbatchev]]></dc:creator>
        <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-05-05-agenda]]></guid>
        <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 May 2014 18:30:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><img class="hide-on-mobile" src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/651740?s=400" style="float: right; margin-left: 1em; width: 100px"/>
As you web application grows, there comes a time when you will want to have scheduled jobs. The easiest thing is of course go the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cron">cron</a> route. However, maintaining and updating it isn&#39;t so easy, especially if you have more than one server to deal with and you still maybe too young for enterprise level job scheduler. What&#39;s left? Maybe just do some <code>setTimeout</code> calls in process... That doesn&#39;t sound very exciting nor very manageable.</p>
<p>This is where <a href="https://github.com/rschmukler/agenda">agenda</a> by <a href="https://github.com/rschmukler">Ryan Schmukler</a> comes in. <a href="https://github.com/rschmukler/agenda">agenda</a>, to plainly put it, is a light-weight job scheduling library for Node.js. Lets give it a go!</p>
<pre><code>npm install agenda
</code></pre><h2 id="features">Features</h2>
<ul>
<li>Minimal overhead. <a href="https://github.com/rschmukler/agenda">agenda</a> aims to keep its code base small.</li>
<li>MongoDB 2.4+ backed persistance layer.</li>
<li>Scheduling with configurable priority, concurrency, and repeating.</li>
<li>Scheduling via cron or human readable syntax.</li>
<li>Event backed job queue that you can hook into.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="usage">Usage</h2>
<p>Lets make a basic example that runs a job 10 seconds after the startup:</p>
<pre><code>var Agenda = require(&#39;agenda&#39;);
var agenda = new Agenda({db: {address: &#39;localhost:27017/agenda-example&#39;}});

agenda.define(&#39;greet the world&#39;, function(job, done) {
  console.log(job.attrs.data.time, &#39;hello world!&#39;);
  done();
});

agenda.schedule(&#39;in 10 seconds&#39;, &#39;greet the world&#39;, {time: new Date()});
agenda.start();

console.log(&#39;Wait 10 seconds...&#39;);
</code></pre><p>Check out <a href="http://runnable.com/U2RE8d2YyYk_iaGU/agenda-module-example-for-npmawesome-nodejitsu-and-node-js">functional example on runnable</a>. I like plain English option, but you can also schedule regular running task with cron style expressions like so:</p>
<pre><code>agenda.every(&#39;*/3 * * * *&#39;, &#39;greet the world&#39;);
</code></pre><p><a href="https://github.com/rschmukler/agenda">agenda</a> is also capable of processing jobs from multiple processes. You just have to specify <code>lockLifetime</code> option during the worker definition.</p>
<pre><code>agenda.define(&#39;someJob&#39;, {lockLifetime: 10000}, function(job, cb) {
  //Do something in 10 seconds or less...
});
</code></pre><h2 id="mongo-vs-redis">Mongo vs Redis</h2>
<p>Curious why MongoDB was chosen for something most would use Redis for? <a href="https://github.com/rschmukler">Ryan Schmukler</a> has a few thoughts on this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The decision to use Mongo instead of Redis is intentional. Redis is often used for non-essential data (such as sessions) and without configuration doesn&#39;t guarantee the same level of persistence as Mongo (should the server need to be restarted/crash).</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/rschmukler/agenda">agenda</a> decides to focus on persistence without requiring special configuration of Redis (thereby degrading the performance of the Redis server on non-critical data, such as sessions).</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing thoughts</h2>
<p><a href="https://github.com/rschmukler/agenda">agenda</a> focuses on setting up and managing regular running tasks such as session purging, email sending, data processing and so on. There are a few alternatives out there:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/learnboost/kue">kue</a> is a priority job queue backed by redis originally written by <a href="https://github.com/visionmedia">TJ Holowaychuk</a> and is currently maintained by <a href="https://github.com/behrad">Behrad</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mattpat/node-schedule">node-schedule</a> is a single process, cron-like and not-cron-like job scheduler by <a href="https://github.com/mattpat">Matt Patenaude</a>. It doesn&#39;t have any external dependencies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
      </item>
    
      
      
      
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[google-distance]]></title>
        <link><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-05-01-google-distance]]></link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Gorbatchev]]></dc:creator>
        <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-05-01-google-distance]]></guid>
        <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 May 2014 18:30:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://npmawesome.com/images/posts/google-distance.png" style="width: 100%" /></p>
<p>Everybody appreciates the distance information between two locations in web mapping services like <a href="http://maps.google.com">Google Maps</a>, right? Do you have a similar use case within your application but want to avoid the implementation overhead of abstracting from an external API? <a href="https://github.com/edwlook/node-google-distance">google-distance</a> by <a href="https://github.com/edwlook">Edward Look</a> helps you to do just that.</p>
<div class="read-more"></div>

<p>The module wraps the distance calculation functionality of the <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/distancematrix/">Google Distance Matrix API</a> into an <em>easy-to-use</em> interface.</p>
<pre><code>npm install google-distance
</code></pre><h2 id="usage">Usage</h2>
<p>Let&#39;s say we want to calculate the distance between New York City and San Diego. <a href="https://github.com/edwlook/node-google-distance">google-distance</a> is frugal and very intuitive to use in this regard. It asks only for two required properties: <code>origin</code> and <code>destination</code>.</p>
<p>The following basic usage example ...</p>
<pre><code>&#39;use strict&#39;;

var distance = require(&#39;google-distance&#39;);

var options = {
    origin: &#39;New York City, USA&#39;,
    destination: &#39;San Diego, USA&#39;
};

function onDistance (err, result) {
    if (err) {
        return console.error(err);
    }

    console.log(result);
}

distance.get(options, onDistance);
</code></pre><p>will <code>result</code> in:</p>
<pre><code>{
    index: null,
    distance: &#39;4,447 km&#39;,
    distanceValue: 4447040,
    duration: &#39;1 day 17 hours&#39;,
    durationValue: 146399, // in seconds
    origin: &#39;New York, NY, USA&#39;,
    destination: &#39;San Diego, CA, USA&#39;,
    mode: &#39;driving&#39;,
    units: &#39;metric&#39;,
    language: &#39;en&#39;,
    avoid: null,
    sensor: false
}
</code></pre><p>Calculating the distance between cities is cool, isn&#39;t it? But you know what&#39;s even cooler? Determining the distance between two tupels of latitude and longitude values.</p>
<pre><code>&#39;use strict&#39;;

var distance = require(&#39;google-distance&#39;);

var options = {
    origin: &#39;40.759011,-73.984472&#39;,
    destination: &#39;37.810848,-122.267448&#39;
};

function onDistance (err, result) {
    if (err) {
        return console.error(err);
    }

    console.log(result);
}

distance.get(options, onDistance);
</code></pre><p>Fantastico! Beside the distance of the two points, you also see a reverse geocoded <code>origin</code> and <code>destination</code>. Woot!</p>
<pre><code>{ index: null,
  distance: &#39;4,669 km&#39;,
  distanceValue: 4669361,
  duration: &#39;1 day 18 hours&#39;,
  durationValue: 151994,
  origin: &#39;165-199 West 47th Street, New York, NY 10036, USA&#39;,
  destination: &#39;400-438 22nd Street, Oakland, CA 94612, USA&#39;,
  mode: &#39;driving&#39;,
  units: &#39;metric&#39;,
  language: &#39;en&#39;,
  avoid: null,
  sensor: false }
</code></pre><h2 id="fine-tuning">Fine tuning</h2>
<p>If you&#39;re crazy enough to cycle all the way down from Oakland to San Diego for instance and want to check how far it really is, you can measure this as well as switching to imperial units or add other <a href="https://github.com/edwlook/node-google-distance#additional-parameters">additional parameters</a>.</p>
<pre><code>&#39;use strict&#39;;

var distance = require(&#39;google-distance&#39;);

var options = {
    origin: &#39;Oakland, USA&#39;,
    destination: &#39;San Diego, USA&#39;,
    mode: &#39;bicycling&#39;,
    units: &#39;imperial&#39;
};

distance.get(options, onDistance (err, result) {
    // ...
});
</code></pre><p>Checkout this <a href="http://runnable.com/U2IHUgxWgZMpX2Ct/google-distance-example-npmawesome">runnable example</a> to verify that cycling might be a good one-week trip. Whereas walking would be definitely a crazy idea. Do the math :)</p>
<h2 id="api-key">API key</h2>
<p>One last note: It is not necessary to configure an API key in order to use the <a href="https://github.com/edwlook/node-google-distance">google-distance</a> module. But: To avoid exceeding Google&#39;s <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/distancematrix/#Limits">quota</a> it is highly recommended.</p>
<p>Follow these <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/distancematrix/#api_key">steps</a> in order to obtain an API key. After that it is easy to inform the module about your key:</p>
<pre><code>var distance = require(&#39;google-distance&#39;);

distance.apiKey = &#39;YOUR_API_KEY&#39;;
</code></pre>]]></description>
      </item>
    
      
      
      
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Links for Apr 30, 2014]]></title>
        <link><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-04-30-links]]></link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Gorbatchev]]></dc:creator>
        <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-04-30-links]]></guid>
        <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 30 Apr 2014 17:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://npmawesome.com/images/posts/html5.png" style="float: right; width: 150px;"/></p>
<h2 id="articles-slides">Articles &amp; Slides</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.2ality.com/2014/04/required-parameters-es6.html">Handling required parameters in ECMAScript 6</a></li>
<li><a href="http://goodui.org/">A Good User Interface</a> has high conversion rates and is easy to use. In other words, it&#39;s nice to both the business side as well as the people using it.</li>
<li><a href="http://tjanczuk.github.io/edge/">Edge.js</a> - run Node.js and .NET code in-process.</li>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/how-good-an-estimator-are-you-part-ii/">How Good an Estimator Are You? Part II</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The specific goal of the exercise was to estimate at the 90 percent confidence level. There are 10 questions in the quiz, so if you were truly estimating at a 90 percent confidence level, you would have gotten about 9 answers correct.</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/jessicaspacekat/an-introduction-to-designing-css-transitions-using-angularjs">An introduction to designing CSS transitions using AngularJS</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>…examples of how a UI designer without much JS or AngularJS experience can use some of the features built in to AngularJS (with angular-animate) to help them design interactive components and add CSS transitions.</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
</ul>
<div class="read-more"></div>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.codeship.io/2014/04/29/continuous-deployment-heroku-bitbucket-nodejs.html">Continuous Deployment for node.js apps from Bitbucket to Heroku</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>How to set up Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment for a Node.js Application from Bitbucket to Heroku</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li><p><a href="http://makezine.com/2014/02/19/designing-a-vinyl-toy-with-joe-ledbetter/">Designing a Vinyl Toy with Joe Ledbetter</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>It all starts with an initial idea or concept for a toy. In this case I wanted to base this project on my popular character called Mr. Bunny. Mr. Bunny has been depicted in my paintings since I first began showing in galleries over 10 years ago.</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li><p><a href="http://makezine.com/2014/04/22/paper-thin-arduino-enables-diy-dirigible/">Printoo</a> is a platform of paper-thin circuit boards and modules. It gives makers an open-source, lightweight, flexible, and modular Arduino-compatible platform to create just about anything you want! What makes Printoo amazingly unique is that it comes with a range of printed electronics modules previously unavailable to the public. These are electronics building &quot;blocks&quot; of the future, only not so rigid.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="github">Github</h2>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://depthy.stamina.pl/">Depthy</a> extracts depth map and original from photos made with Google Camera&#39;s Lens Blur. I think this is the future of product photography (until there’s proper 3D).</p>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.npmjs.org/package/flowdock-stream">flowdock-stream</a> is a node module for streaming <a href="https://www.flowdock.com/">flowdock</a> flows.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="chrome">Chrome</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://projectnaptha.com/">Project Naptha</a> automatically applies state-of-the-art computer vision algorithms on every image you see while browsing the web. The result is a seamless and intuitive experience, where you can highlight as well as copy and paste and even edit and translate the text formerly trapped within an image.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="twitter">Twitter</h2>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"><p>Breathalyzers for cars? Breathalyzers for Twitter! I’d probably buy one, just to be 100% safe.</p>&mdash; Axel Rauschmayer (@rauschma) <a href="https://twitter.com/rauschma/statuses/459111786382639104">April 23, 2014</a></blockquote>]]></description>
      </item>
    
      
      
      
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[sentiment]]></title>
        <link><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-04-30-sentiment]]></link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Gorbatchev]]></dc:creator>
        <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-04-30-sentiment]]></guid>
        <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 30 Apr 2014 16:24:35 GMT]]></pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[<p>Sentiment analysis is one of those things you don&#39;t get to do very often, as cool as it sounds. It&#39;s one of those things I always wanted to do but haven&#39;t had a reason to yet. The field of natural language is as deep and complex as you want it to be. <a href="http://nlp.stanford.edu/sentiment/">Stanford Sentiment Analysis</a> is a pretty massive project and nets pretty decent results.</p>
<p><img class="hide-on-mobile" src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/747641?s=400" style="float: right; margin-left: 1em; width: 100px"/>
<a href="https://github.com/thisandagain/sentiment">sentiment</a> module by <a href="https://github.com/thisandagain">Andrew Sliwinski</a> takes a very simple approach to the problem of just counting token words and their preassigned weight. For the most part you can expect pretty average results and it gets completely lost with expressions like &quot;I don&#39;t know half of you half as well as I should like, and I like less than half of you half as well as you deserve&quot; (frankly I don&#39;t understand what it says either). But the cool thing is - it actually works and you don&#39;t need a giant database. <a href="https://github.com/thisandagain/sentiment">sentiment</a> can get you started down the path until you feel the need for something more involved.</p>
<div class="read-more"></div>

<pre><code>npm install sentiment
</code></pre><h2 id="features">Features</h2>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thisandagain/sentiment">sentiment</a> uses the <a href="http://www2.imm.dtu.dk/pubdb/views/publication_details.php?id=6010">AFINN-111</a> wordlist to perform sentiment analysis on arbitrary blocks of input text and provides serveral things:</p>
<ul>
<li>Performance</li>
<li>The ability to append and overwrite word / value pairs from the AFINN wordlist</li>
<li>A build process that makes updating sentiment to future versions of the AFINN word list trivial</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="usage">Usage</h2>
<p>Here&#39;s a simple example analysing bunch of latest <a href="https://www.twitter.com/dhh">DHH tweets</a>.</p>
<pre><code>var
  request = require(&#39;request&#39;),
  cheerio = require(&#39;cheerio&#39;),
  sentiment = require(&#39;sentiment&#39;)
  ;

function sentimentToSmiley(sentiment) {
  var score = sentiment.score;

  if(score === 0) { return &#39;:-|&#39; }
  if(score &lt; 0) {
    if(score &gt; -2) { return &#39;:-(&#39; }
    return &#39;:`(&#39;
  }

  if(score &lt; 2) { return &#39;:-)&#39; }
  return &#39;:-D&#39;
}

request(&#39;https://www.twitter.com/dhh&#39;, function(err, response) {
  var $ = cheerio.load(response.body);

  $(&#39;.tweet-text&#39;).toArray().forEach(function(item) {
    var text = $(item).text();
    var results = sentiment(text);
    console.log(sentimentToSmiley(results), &#39;-&#39;, text.replace(/\n/g, &#39; &#39;));
  });
});
</code></pre><p>Checkout out <a href="http://runnable.com/U1aiDzGWpo8vHVFK/sentiment-analysis-with-node-js-for-nodejitsu-and-npmawesome">functional example on runnable</a>. Running this will produce result similiar to:</p>
<pre><code>:-| - @mrbigdreamerYWF We tried to get NBC but they wouldn&#39;t cover it :)
:-| - @AmianExclusive I think the C7R is the most expensive customer GTE car you can buy. And still not a proven thing.
:-| - @AmianExclusive Corvette factory team will be at Le Mans but not Viper :(. Apparently they didn&#39;t sell enough cars to afford it.
:-| - Goooood morning #RailsConf! My talk is at 9:15am central. It will be streamed live on justin.tv/confreaks, if you&#39;re not in Chicago.
:-| - @ashesfall Hot diggity.
:-) - (Yes, internet is fast elsewhere too, but most services of note have their app servers in the US, so that&#39;s the ping that counts).
:-| - @arunagw Just about everything on the internet of note, which happens to have app servers in the US :D
:-| - For those who can&#39;t attend RailsConf, we&#39;ll be livestreaming the keynotes here: justin.tv/confreaks Schedule here: railsconf.com/schedule
:-D - It gets me every time I&#39;m back in the US - even if just out for a few weeks: 20ms pings is internet happiness. So fast.
:-| - @turbineseaplane Nope. May depend on hand size? Could see it be harder to hold with small hands.
:-| - @mhauer I find that the hybrid model is actually the most common in anything but the newest or smallest companies. Very workable.
:-( - @N8Gard @railsconf They&#39;re going to record it, I think. So no worries.
:-( - @dennismajor1 @thereaIbanksy I&#39;d prefer to look at it the other way: drop the religious nonsense and enjoy a party without sin!
:-| - @turbineseaplane It is sometimes a little awkward but the sacrifice is worth it.
:-| - @andrestuul Right on the last one, not on the first two. Connecting has never been easier. 10 yrs ago I was working from Denmark.
:-| - @davegreiner @dhh we had thousands of accounts on Cork’d when it was still on a Mac mini in my friend’s rack (Rails 1.x)
:`( - @GregMolnar Horrible contortions to the false idol of testing. More on this in my keynote at RailsConf tomorrow.
:-D - @dhh Sounds familiar. CM was hosted on a cheap box with all our client&#39;s sites. Went dedicated when it started slowing them down 1 yr later.
:`( - @thomasfuchs @letsfreckle Fuck yeah! But you did have to forgo such necessities as a big fancy office on day 1!
:-) - @homakov @davidpetschull I was in Denmark while I built Basecamp. But yes timezone and language can be barriers.
</code></pre><h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing thoughts</h2>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thisandagain/sentiment">sentiment</a> is a very simple token counter which has vocabulary of about 2.5k english words. It doesn&#39;t always produce reliable results, but it gets you a step forward if you need to do sentiment analysis without bringing in the heavy weight APIs or expensive commercial libraries.</p>
<p>I can totally imagine processing customer inquiries coming in via email, twitter and other channels with <a href="https://github.com/thisandagain/sentiment">sentiment</a>. Higher priority could be assigned to inquires with lower, more negative scores.</p>
]]></description>
      </item>
    
      
      
      
      <item>
        <title><![CDATA[Comparing Express, Restify, hapi and LoopBack for building RESTful APIs]]></title>
        <link><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-04-29-compare-express-restify-hapi-loopback]]></link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Gorbatchev]]></dc:creator>
        <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[http://npmawesome.com/posts/2014-04-29-compare-express-restify-hapi-loopback]]></guid>
        <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 29 Apr 2014 17:01:54 GMT]]></pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[<p>If you are writing a Node.js application, chances are you going to have some kind of API end points to be consumed by your frond end or expose data for others to take in. This is where <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer">RESTful APIs</a> come in. And now you have a dilemma - what tools to use and what approach to take? So many choices...</p>
<p><img src="http://npmawesome.com/images/posts/compare-express-restify-hapi-loopback/confused.gif"/></p>
<p>Thanks to the incredibly active Node.js community, the amount of results for a <a href="https://www.npmjs.org/search?q=rest">&quot;rest&quot; search on NPM</a> is pretty overwhelming. Everyone has their own implementation and approach, but few seem to agree on a common way to go about implementing RESTful APIs in Node.js.</p>
<div class="read-more"></div>

<h2 id="restful-apis-with-express">RESTful APIs with Express</h2>
<p>The most common approach is to just roll your own end points with <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a>. This practice allows you to get started quickly, but it becomes burdensome in the long run. Lets look at pros and cons:</p>
<h3 id="example">Example</h3>
<p>Here&#39;s what a typical end point might look like in <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a> using the latest 4.x <code>Router</code> feature:</p>
<pre><code>var express = require(&#39;express&#39;);
var Item = require(&#39;models&#39;).Item;
var app = express();
var itemRoute = express.Router();

itemRoute.param(&#39;itemId&#39;, function(req, res, next, id) {
  Item.findById(req.params.itemId, function(err, item) {
    req.item = item;
    next();
  });
});

itemRoute.route(&#39;/:itemId&#39;)
  .get(function(req, res, next) {
    res.json(req.item);
  })
  .put(function(req, res, next) {
    req.item.set(req.body);
    req.item.save(function(err, item) {
      res.json(item);
    });
  })
  .post(function(req, res, next) {
    var item = new Item(req.body);
    item.save(function(err, item) {
      res.json(item);
    });
  })
  .delete(function(req, res, next) {
    req.item.remove(function(err) {
      res.json({});
    });
  })
  ;

app.use(&#39;/api/items&#39;, itemRoute);
app.listen(8080);
</code></pre><h3 id="pros">Pros</h3>
<ol>
<li>Little learning curve, <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a> is nearly a standard for Node.js web application</li>
<li>Fully customizable</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="cons">Cons</h3>
<ol>
<li>All end points need to be created manually, you end up doing a lot of the same code (or worse, start rolling your own libraries after a while)</li>
<li>Every end point needs to be tested (or at the very least I recommend that you hit the end points with HTTP consumer to make sure they are actually there and don&#39;t throw 500s)</li>
<li>Refactoring becomes painful because everything needs to be updated everywhere</li>
<li>Doesn&#39;t come with anything &quot;standard&quot;, have to figure out your own approach</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a> is a great starting point, but eventually you will feel the pain of &quot;roll your own&quot; approach.</p>
<h2 id="restful-apis-with-restify">RESTful APIs with Restify</h2>
<p><a href="http://mcavage.me/node-restify">Restify</a> is a relatively old player in the Node.js API field, very stable and being actively developed. It is built specifically to enable you to build correct REST web services and intentionally borrows heavily from <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a>.</p>
<h3 id="example">Example</h3>
<p>Because <a href="http://mcavage.me/node-restify">Restify</a> borrows from <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a>, the syntax is nearly identical:</p>
<pre><code>var restify = require(&#39;restify&#39;);
var Item = require(&#39;models&#39;).Item;
var app = restify.createServer()

app.use(function(req, res, next) {
  if (req.params.itemId) {
    Item.findById(req.params.itemId, function(err, item) {
      req.item = item;
      next();
    });
  }
  else {
    next();
  }
});

app.get(&#39;/api/items/:itemId&#39;, function(req, res, next) {
  res.send(200, req.item);
});

app.put(&#39;/api/items/:itemId&#39;, function(req, res, next) {
  req.item.set(req.body);
  req.item.save(function(err, item) {
    res.send(204, item);
  });
});

app.post(&#39;/api/items/:itemId&#39;, function(req, res, next) {
  var item = new Item(req.body);
  item.save(function(err, item) {
    res.send(201, item);
  });
});

app.delete(&#39;/api/items/:itemId&#39;, function(req, res, next) {
  req.item.remove(function(err) {
    res.send(204, {});
  });
});

app.listen(8080);
</code></pre><h3 id="pros">Pros</h3>
<ul>
<li>Automatic DTrace support for all your handlers (if you&#39;re running on a platform that supports DTrace)</li>
<li>Doesn&#39;t have unnecessary functionality like templating and rendering</li>
<li>Built in throttling</li>
<li>Built in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SPDY">SPDY</a> support</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="cons">Cons</h3>
<p>The cons are all the same with <a href="http://mcavage.me/node-restify">Restify</a> as they are with <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a>, lots of manual labor.</p>
<h2 id="restful-apis-with-hapi">RESTful APIs with hapi</h2>
<p><a href="http://spumko.github.io/">hapi</a> is a lesser known Node.js framework that is getting momentum thanks to fulltime support of the Walmart Labs team. It takes a somewhat different approach from <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a> and <a href="http://mcavage.me/node-restify">Restify</a> by providing significantly more functionality out of the box for building web servers.</p>
<h3 id="example">Example</h3>
<p>Here&#39;s the same example re-written using <a href="http://spumko.github.io/">hapi</a>:</p>
<pre><code>var Hapi = require(&#39;hapi&#39;);
var Item = require(&#39;models&#39;).Item;
var server = Hapi.createServer(&#39;0.0.0.0&#39;, 8080);

server.ext(&#39;onPreHandler&#39;, function(req, next) {
  if (req.params.itemId) {
    Item.findById(req.params.itemId, function(err, item) {
      req.item = item;
      next();
    });
  }
  else {
    next();
  }
});

server.route([
  {
    path: &#39;/api/items/{itemId}&#39;,
    method: &#39;GET&#39;,
    config: {
      handler: function(req, reply) {
        reply(req.item);
      }
    }
  },
  {
    path: &#39;/api/items&#39;,
    method: &#39;PUT&#39;,
    config: {
      handler: function(req, reply) {
        req.item.set(req.body);
        req.item.save(function(err, item) {
          res.send(204, item);
        });
      }
    }
  },
  {
    path: &#39;/api/items&#39;,
    method: &#39;POST&#39;,
    config: {
      handler: function(req, reply) {
        var item = new Item(req.body);
        item.save(function(err, item) {
          res.send(201, item);
        });
      }
    }
  },
  {
    path: &#39;/api/items/{itemId}&#39;,
    method: &#39;DELETE&#39;,
    config: {
      handler: function(req, reply) {
        req.item.remove(function(err) {
          res.send(204, {});
        });
      }
    }
  }
]);

server.start();
</code></pre><h3 id="pros">Pros</h3>
<ol>
<li>Very granular control over request handling</li>
<li>Detailed API <a href="https://github.com/spumko/hapi/blob/master/docs/Reference.md">reference</a> with support for documentation generation</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="cons">Cons</h3>
<p>As with <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a> and <a href="http://mcavage.me/node-restify">Restify</a>, <a href="http://spumko.github.io/">hapi</a> gives you great construction blocks, but you are left to your own devices figuring out how to use them.</p>
<h2 id="what-else-is-there-">What else is there?</h2>
<p><a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a>, <a href="http://mcavage.me/node-restify">Restify</a> and <a href="http://spumko.github.io/">hapi</a> are all great starting points, but in the long run it might not be the right choice if you plan on investing heavily into APIs.</p>
<h2 id="loopback">LoopBack</h2>
<p><a href="http://strongloop.com/mobile-application-development/loopback/">LoopBack</a> by <a href="http://strongloop.com">StrongLoop</a> is a fully featured Node.js backend framework to connect your consumer applications with data. It adopts <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convention_over_configuration">convention over configuration</a> mantra popularized by Ruby on Rails.</p>
<h3 id="example">Example</h3>
<pre><code>var loopback = require(&#39;loopback&#39;);
var Item = require(&#39;./models&#39;).Item;
var app = module.exports = loopback();

app.model(Item);
app.use(&#39;/api&#39;, loopback.rest());
app.listen(8080);
</code></pre><p>There&#39;s a lot of &quot;magic&quot; happening in the background. But with just 6 lines of code you now have the following end points:</p>
<pre><code>DELETE /items/{id}
GET /items
GET /items/count
GET /items/findOne
GET /items/{id}
GET /items/{id}/exists
POST /items
PUT /items
PUT /items/{id}
</code></pre><p><img src="http://npmawesome.com/images/posts/compare-express-restify-hapi-loopback/mind-blowing-nph.gif"/></p>
<p>To start exploring your own APIs right away, there&#39;s a bundled <code>explorer</code> module that you can attach to your application:</p>
<pre><code>var explorer = require(&#39;loopback-explorer&#39;);
app.use(&#39;/explorer&#39;, explorer(app, {basePath: &#39;/api&#39;}));
</code></pre><p>And now opening <code>http://localhost:8080/explorer</code> you get this:</p>
<p><img src="http://npmawesome.com/images/posts/compare-express-restify-hapi-loopback/screenshot.png"/></p>
<p>Seriously cool stuff!</p>
<h3 id="pros">Pros</h3>
<ol>
<li>Very quick RESTful API development</li>
<li>Convention over configuration</li>
<li>Built in models ready to use</li>
<li>RPC support</li>
<li>Fully configurable when needed</li>
<li>Extensive documentation</li>
<li>Fulltime team working on the project</li>
<li>Available commercial support</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="cons">Cons</h3>
<ol>
<li>Learning curve can be pretty steep because there are so many moving parts</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="rpc">RPC</h2>
<p>The <a href="http://strongloop.com/mobile-application-development/loopback/">LoopBack</a> example above is so tiny, I feel bad about it. How about we extend it with a quick RPC endpoint to balance things out?</p>
<pre><code>var loopback = require(&#39;loopback&#39;);
var explorer = require(&#39;loopback-explorer&#39;);
var remoting = require(&#39;strong-remoting&#39;);
var Item = require(&#39;./models&#39;).Item;
var app = module.exports = loopback();
var rpc = remoting.create();

function echo(ping, callback) {
  callback(null, ping);
}

echo.shared = true;
echo.accepts = {arg: &#39;ping&#39;};
echo.returns = {arg: &#39;echo&#39;};

rpc.exports.system = {
  echo: echo
};

app.model(Item);
app.use(&#39;/api&#39;, loopback.rest());
app.use(&#39;/explorer&#39;, explorer(app, {basePath: &#39;/api&#39;}));
app.use(&#39;/rpc&#39;, rpc.handler(&#39;rest&#39;));
app.listen(8080);
</code></pre><p>And now you can do this:</p>
<pre><code>$ curl &quot;http://localhost:8080/rpc/system/echo?ping=hello&quot;
{
  &quot;echo&quot;: &quot;hello&quot;
}
</code></pre><p><img src="http://npmawesome.com/images/posts/compare-express-restify-hapi-loopback/thumbs-up-nph.gif"/></p>
<h2 id="what-s-next-">What&#39;s next?</h2>
<ul>
<li>Install LoopBack with a <a href="http://strongloop.com/get-started/">simple npm command</a>.</li>
<li>Read <a href="http://docs.strongloop.com/display/DOC/LoopBack">LoopBack documentation</a>.</li>
<li>Need performance monitoring, profiling and cluster capabilites for your Node apps? Check out <a href="http://strongloop.com/node-js-performance/strongops/">StrongOps</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>